MAULI PATEL

Cleveland, OHIO, 44118

216-551-5887 - mauli.p@outlook.com - linkedin.com/in/maulipatel247

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated graduate student specializing in Biomedical and Health Informatics, skilled in data analytics and programming, with a strong academic foundation. Committed to harnessing the power of data to drive innovation in healthcare, improve patient care, and advance the industry. I am enthusiastic about applying my multidisciplinary skills and passion for healthcare technology to create a significant impact in the field of health informatics.

SKILLS

- Problem Solving & Critical Thinking
- Adaptive Learning
- Leadership
- Collaboration & Communication
- Customer relations
- Microsoft Office

- Project Management
- Data Entry & Management
- Programming (JS, Html, Python, R)
- Data Analytics
- STEM Skills
- Marketing

EDUCATION

Expected in 08/2024 M.Sc. Biomedical and Health Informatics

Case Western Reserve University

Enrolling GPA 3.89

06/2023 B.Sc. Psychology

University of Manitoba

Dean Honor List (3 consecutive years), President Scholar & Queen Elizabeth Tier III Scholarship

06/2018 Advance Placement (AP)

Murdoch MacKay Collegiate

Presidents Honor List & School District Student of the Year (2018)

WORK HISTORY

04/2023 to 08/2023

Sales and Marketing Lead

Mississauga Fine Arts Academy

- Managed client base of over 600 clients and coordinated schedules for 30+ academy instructors.
- Spearheaded marketing and data analysis for the academy, resulting in increased visibility and enrollment.
- Implemented and managed Daily Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) to ensure smooth operations.
- Handled client and academy instructor payments and invoices efficiently, maintaining financial records.
- Developed and executed ongoing promotional campaigns to attract over 200+ clients and generate leads and increase sales revenue.
- Orchestrated and facilitated corporate meetings to foster collaboration and strategic planning, demonstrating advanced multitasking abilities in efficiently coordinating schedules and tasks.

09/2018 to 08/2023

Naval Combat Boatswain

Canadian Armed Forces

 Canadian Armed Forces (CAF) Seamanship Specialists: Ensure safe military operations and maintain ship rigging and cargo handling equipment.

- Responded quickly to crisis situations, balancing operational requirements against public safety to effectively handle dynamic needs.
- Monitored communications to detect important information related to current and planned military operations.
- Trained in search and rescue, first-aid, weapons handling, and fire/sea safety to support mission readiness.

01/2023 to 04/2023

Clinical Coordinator & Physiotherapy Assistant

PhysioVillage Brampton Clinic

- Preparing and administering prescriptions and referrals, managing patient charts and EMRs, preparing and maintaining medical equipment, and assisting with various patient procedures.
- Responsible for maintaining patient records, scheduling appointments, filing claims, and handling insurance matters.
- Extended my role and served as secondary key holder, assisting with inventory management and overseeing SOPs.
- Responsible for promoting business and contributing to marketing efforts, recruiting new employees, and providing training to additional staff members.

10/2019 to 09/2022

Non-Public Funds Manager & Executive Administrative Assistant Canadian Armed Forces

- Assisted Financial Services Administrators and Operations manager in accounting and private fund management.
- Oversaw budgeting, forecasting, and financial reporting, optimizing fund utilization and implemented cost-saving measures, resulting in improved fund efficiency and allocation.
- Produced accurate and timely reports, summaries, and briefings for decision-makers to maintain effective communication channels.
- Conducted data analysis to maintain accurate and auditable records while supporting strategic decision-making.
- Got promoted to perform the duties of a Regulating Petty Officer at base headquarters maintaining SOPs, providing departmental collaboration.

05/2021 to 09/2021

Research Assistant

Pascoe Lab & Health Science Center

- Collaborated with Dr. Chris Pascoe and Dr. Biniam Kidane in the Department of Pneumothorax Surgery.
- Conducted 200+ patient interviews both before and after surgery, ensuring comprehensive data collection and data analysis.
- Organized and analyzed a diverse dataset, including discrete and qualitative data points.
- Regularly conducted patient follow-up calls and categorized patient records for efficient retrieval and analysis.
- Worked both independently and collaboratively in fast-paced laboratory environment.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Psychology Games/Experiment Programming, Attention & Learning Lab
- Vice President, MedLife University of Manitoba
- Shadowing Director, Pre-Dental Society Professional Student Association
- Shadowing Internship Program, Piedmont Atlanta Cardiac Rehab
- Treasurer, Pre-PA Society Professional Student Association
- Patient Care Volunteer, WISH Clinic
- Volunteer, Student-Senior Isolation Prevention Partnership x COVID (SSIPP)
- Student Ambassador, U of M Orientation & Welcome Committee
- Emergency Care Volunteer, Concordia Hospital